Andreas Ellwanger, B.Sc. Curriculum Vitæ

Friedrichstr. 30 80801 Munich Germany +49 160 99133688 mail@andreasellwanger.com https://www.andreasellwanger.com

Summary

Andreas, a postgraduate student, currently pursues Computer Science at the Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, Germany and the Leiden University, The Netherlands. He graduated in April 2018 at the LMU Munich with a Bachelor of Science in Media Informatics and Human-Computer Interaction. At the moment Andreas works remotely for a Berlin-based startup called Aiderly GmbH as a Full Stack Developer / UX Researcher. Since last year he is part of the Tech4Germany fellowship, Germany's first e-Government fellowship with Germany's Chief of Staff Prof. Helge Braun as patron. Therefore he had been staying in Berlin, Germany for three months to work as a UX Researcher as well as a Frontend Developer for the German government. Together with eight other fellows, they worked on topics related to digitalisation and e-government.

Work experience

12/2018 - Aiderly GmbH, Berlin, Germany

Full Stack Developer / UX Researcher

- UX Design (User Experience)

- Design and development of new features

- Maintenance and adaptation of existing features of the Aiderly software

08/2018 - 10/2018 Tech4Germany, Berlin, Germany

Frontend Developer / UX Researcher

06/2015 - 08/2015 Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, Germany

Tutor in Computer Science

Education

02/2019 - Leiden University, The Netherlands

Computer Science

Erasmus+

04/2018 - Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, Germany

Computer Science

Pursued degree: Master of Science - M.Sc.

10/2013 - 04/2018 Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, Germany

Media Informatics with Minor Human-Computer Interaction Degree: Bachelor of Science - B.Sc. (Grade 2,1), April 2018

Advisor: Axel Hösl

05/2011 - 09/2013 Technical University of Munich, Germany and

Ludwig Maximilian University of Munich, Germany

Bioinformatics

09/2001 - 05/2011 Christoph-Scheiner-Gymnasium Ingolstadt, Germany

Degree: Allgemeine Hochschulreife ("Abitur"), May 2011

Andreas Ellwanger Curriculum Vitæ

Volunteer experience

2013 -2014 Lewis and Clark College

Mentor of the "Year of Study in Munich" program

Certification

24 June 2016 Leipzig University of Applied Sciences

English in Computer Science and Information Technology

at level C1.1 CEF (Grade 1,0)

- Research -

See also my publication profiles at ACM Digital Library, DBLP, Google Scholar and ORCID.

Papers

2018 ACM

Andreas Ellwanger, Axel Hoesl, and Andreas Butz. 2018. Axis- plus Content-based Control for Camera Drones: Design and Evaluation of User Interface Concepts. In Proceedings of the 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems, and Applications (DroNet'18). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 9-14. DOI: 10.1145/3213526.3213529

Talks

15 June 2018 4th ACM Workshop on Micro Aerial Vehicle Networks, Systems,

and Applications (DroNet 2018) @ MobiSys 2018

Full paper presentation

- Miscellaneous -

See also my private profiles at GitHub, Keybase and Twitter.

Languages German (native), English (fluent)

Skills Java, Scala, C#, Python, JavaScript, R, Git, REST, SQL, HTML/CSS

Just now studying - React, Haskell, Rust

Organizations LMU Alumni Informatik e.V.